

🔍 +57 3218477149

Nicolás Rubio García

Data analyst

ABOUT

Political Science and Economics student, certified data analyst, and enthusiast of web programming. About to graduate as a political scientist, and looking forward to a Master's in Data Science. I have authored articles and participated as a speaker at national congresses, with experience in the development and management of research projects, as well as in the analysis and modeling of massive datasets.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Consultant

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, December 2023 - December 2023

- Collaboration in the design and implementation of the comprehensive monitoring and evaluation system for the Corporation.
- · Generation of accurate and relevant statistical inputs for the Management Report corresponding to the year 2023.
- Creation of detailed maps for regional characterization.

Freelance Data Analyst

Freelance, March 2023 - Present

- Development of an innovative methodology to measure the performance of healthcare systems in Latin America.
- Analysis and modeling of data extracted from the GEIH 2022-2023.
- · Detailed characterization of various indicators to drive regional development in Magdalena Centro.

Political Science Intern - Data Analyst

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, June 2023 - December 2023

- Comprehensive diagnosis and update of databases.
- Thorough analysis and detailed evaluation of data.
- · Creation of executive reports synthesizing and effectively communicating findings.
- Development of specialized documents for municipal characterization.

LANGUAGES

English Spanish



PORTFOLIO AND NETWORKS



CERTIFICATION

Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate, 2024

Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Certificate, 2023

Data cleaning and preprocessing - Outstanding,

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Political Science, 2019 - 2023 (Awaiting the graduation ceremony).

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, 2021 - Present.

Science and Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp, 2023 - Present.

Diploma in Programming Skills with Emphasis on Websites, 2022.

Diploma in Applied Statistics and Applied Econometrics, 2023

SKILLS

Técnicas	Blandas
R	Resolución de
Python	problemas
MySQL	Trabajo en equipo
Power BI	Comunicación
Investigación	Escucha activa



🔍 +57 3218477149

Nicolás Rubio García

Data analyst

ABOUT

Certified data analyst, political Science and Economics student, and enthusiast of web programming. About to graduate as a political scientist, and looking forward to a Master's in Data Science. I have authored articles and participated as a speaker at national congresses, with experience in the development and management of research projects, as well as in the analysis and modeling of massive datasets.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Consultant

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, December 2023 - December 2023

- Collaboration in the design and implementation of the comprehensive monitoring and evaluation system for the Corporation.
- · Generation of accurate and relevant statistical inputs for the Management Report corresponding to the year 2023.
- Creation of detailed maps for regional characterization.

Freelance Data Analyst

Freelance, March 2023 - Present

- Development of an innovative methodology to measure the performance of healthcare systems in Latin America.
- Analysis and modeling of data extracted from the GEIH 2022-2023.
- · Detailed characterization of various indicators to drive regional development in Magdalena Centro.

Political Science Intern - Data Analyst

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, June 2023 - December 2023

- Comprehensive diagnosis and update of databases.
- Thorough analysis and detailed evaluation of data.
- · Creation of executive reports synthesizing and effectively communicating findings.
- Development of specialized documents for municipal characterization.

LANGUAGES



PORTFOLIO AND NETWORKS



CERTIFICATION

Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate, 2024

Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Certificate, 2023

Data cleaning and preprocessing - Outstanding,

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Political Science, 2019 - 2023 (Awaiting the graduation ceremony).

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, 2021 - Present.

Science and Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp, 2023 - Present.

Diploma in Programming Skills with Emphasis on Websites, 2022.

Diploma in Applied Statistics and Applied Econometrics, 2023

SKILLS

Hard	Soft
R	Problem solving
Python	Teamwork
MySQL	Communication
Power BI	Active listening
Statistics	Critical thinking
Econometrics	
Research	